# **Amy Paslak**







# Summary

Stumbling into web design at a young age, I've been building apps, websites, and tools for over 15 years. I love solving problems and digging into code to determine how it works or could be improved. I absorb everything I can about my work and aspire to deliver elegant, scalable, and reliable code.

I love what I do, and aim to grow with like-minded engineers, building amazing tech.

# Experience

# Venmo — July 2019-present

#### MTS 1 Software Engineer

- Joined the experience team as a backend engineer, picking up Python and Django.
- Led a major project that required coordination between three teams across the stack to rewrite existing functionality into a more scalable, feature-rich architecture.
- Technical lead for Venmo's credit card, which launched in October 2020 after about 10 months of active development.

### Vibes Media — May 2012-July 2019

#### Senior Software Engineer / Team Lead

- Lead an agile team to maintain and improve an outdated CRM, built on Ruby/Rails with a Backbone.js and React front end.
- Championed and implemented a large UI overhaul, which brought the look and feel of the CRM up to date with modern styling, as well as allowed the team to clean up unused and duplicated styles across the platform.
- Member of team that successfully migrated the CRM from company-owned servers into AWS.

#### Software Engineer II / Team Lead

- Lead a team of contractors to update the CRM from Rails 2.3 & Ruby 1.8.7 to Rails 3.2 & Ruby 2.1, with active development ongoing.
- Brief foray into contract work, where I built a small greeting card app and a lightweight conversation engine that integrated into the CRM.

- Mentored junior members of the team.
- Deployed new code at a regular cadence.

#### Software Engineer I

- Introduced better code quality and standardization with code reviews and linting tools
- Mentored other engineers about common QA practices, as our team functioned without an official QA engineer.

#### **Quality Assurance Engineer**

- Maintained and expanded the automated test suite.
- Documented and manually tested new features.

# **Skills**

#### Languages and Frameworks

- ∘ Python Django
- Ruby Rails, Rspec, Capybara, Selenium, Jekyll
- o Javascript jQuery, Node.js, Backbone.js, Jasmine, React

#### **Data Systems**

- o Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Data Stores Redis

#### Miscellaneous

- Text Editors Vim, Emacs, SpaceMacs
- Version Control Git
- Infrastructure Chef, Capistrano, Jenkins, Travis

### Education

# Illinois Institute of Technology (IIT) — 2008-2012

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Minor in Psychology
- Information Security specialization
- Alpha Sigma Alpha sorority member